<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-02-09T11:30:20-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Absolute AppSec - The Blog</title><subtitle>A BLOG FOR THOSE WHO LIKE ABSOLUTE APPSEC AND BLOGS, TOO</subtitle><entry><title type="html">AppSec For New Professionals</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/new/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AppSec For New Professionals" /><published>2022-02-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-02-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/appsec-for-new</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/new/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-into-application-security-can-be-daunting-but-there-is-a-way&quot;&gt;Getting into Application Security can be daunting, but there is a way&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As podcasters, we are often asked what it takes to get into Application Security. While there is no “one true way” to get into Application Security, we have talked with individuals on the podcast with a range of backgrounds, from coding or engineering to circus performers (seriously). All it takes is a desire to learn, time to explore different application security topics, and to get involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So where to start? It is often said that the best application security engineers were software engineers in the past. While the ability to code enterprise applications is definitely a plus, it is not a hard and fast requirement. That being said, the ability to read code and understand application interactions is a definite advantage to finding and fixing application flaws. When facing a language, or framework without prior experience, one of the first things to do is read the documentation, follow a tutorial, and write a small hello-world application using that specific technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, if you don’t know how to build or code applications, there is no wrong place to start. Jump into the deep end and build a web application using Node Express, Ruby on Rails, or Django. Or go the mobile route and build something using React Native, Android Studio, or Apple’s XCode. Each tutorial and coding step will teach you how developers think. If you are just starting with code, stick with the basics of Python or JavaScript to get going. There are a multitude of online tutorials for both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have prior coding experience, but are inexperienced with security vulnerabilities and flaws, start with the Open Web Application Security Project’s (OWASP) Top 10 Web Application Security Risks (https://owasp.org/www-project-top-ten/). OWASP is a nonprofit group of security and software engineers that works to improve software security through awareness, tools, and a number of different projects. Learn to identify the above risks and exploit them using one of the many intentionally vulnerable application (e.g. OWASP Juice Shop, WebGoat, DVWS) and an intercepting proxy (OWASP ZAP, Burp Suite). This process will get you started thinking offensively about how an application is built and how security weaknesses are identified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once familiar with common risks, vulnerabilities and exploits, your personal path is dependent on your current role and responsibilities. If you are employed as a developer, look for vulnerabilities within your own code and application, as long as you have permission to do so. In addition, most organizations are implementing or have implemented what is known as security champions programs. Take advantage of these programs to expand your knowledge and interact with others in your company responsible for and interested in security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a student or currently not involved in any development projects, bug bounty programs make it easy to explore and search for security vulnerabilities in real-world applications. The two most popular programs are currently Hacker One (hackerone.com) and Bug Crowd (bugcrowd.com). Stick to the scoped targets, but don’t be afraid to try looking for common issues, even if the target has been running a bug bounty program for a long time. If you find a security flaw, report it back through the program, document a step-by-step process to exploit the issue, and provide recommendations for mitigating the problem. If you don’t have an idea how the mitigation should happen, research the issue and expand your own knowledge on the issue before reporting the vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have decided to go down the application security path, get involved with your local community either through conferences or local meetups. We can’t stress enough how much making in-person connections has affected our application security careers. OWASP and DEF CON Group chapters exist all over the world and meet monthly in most locations. While some topics are advanced, chapter leaders are happy to include topics that are applicable to all and help others get into the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conferences are great places to meet people and hear the latest research on advanced topics. Don’t discount the opportunity to hone your security skills through the capture-the-flag (CTF) events that run during most security conferences. At a minimum, most CTFs will include application security targets (e.g. web or mobile applications, API endpoints), while larger conferences like DEF CON (defcon.org) will have specific villages and contests that are application security specific. We have learned more in the past participating in CTFs than attending talks on specific vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you become familiar with different areas of application security, do not be afraid to explore different security activities associated with building applications. For example, you may have a knack for secure code review over penetration testing dynamic sites. Or threat modeling may speak to you more than writing authentication routines. While each activity isn’t always required or requested by different organizations, there are those that value the abilities. In other words, find your niche and what you enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have a target of the job you want, use your network to identify opportunities. Speak up to your colleagues and boss about security in your organization. Volunteer to train others on what you have learned. Explore novel aspects of your chosen topic and blog, present, or otherwise codify your research. The way you explain a topic may help others trying to understand that same topic and will only solidify your own understanding. Put out the resources you wish were available when you started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever you do, enjoy the ride.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>@sethlaw</name></author><category term="appsec" /><category term="career" /><category term="growth" /><category term="newb" /><category term="appsec" /><category term="career" /><category term="growth" /><category term="newb" /><summary type="html">Getting into Application Security can be daunting, but there is a way</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Absolute(ly) Awesome AppSec</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/awesome/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Absolute(ly) Awesome AppSec" /><published>2022-02-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-02-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/awesome-appsec</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/awesome/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources-that-we-have-found-useful-during-our-application-security-careers&quot;&gt;Resources that we have found useful during our Application Security Careers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following resources could also be described as Absolute AppSec’s Awesome Application Security list. Either way, these are all resources that have been helpful to us over the years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;newsletters&quot;&gt;Newsletters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tl;dr sec - &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/clintgibler&quot;&gt;Clint Gibler’s&lt;/a&gt; weekly newsletter covering a range of topics, from application security to red team, cloud security, upcoming conferences, and miscellaneous topics that are security related. &lt;a href=&quot;https://tldrsec.com&quot;&gt;tl;dr sec&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unsupervised Learning - Daniel Miesser spends 20+ hours each week consuming content and summarizes articles on security, technology, and other topics. &lt;a href=&quot;https://danielmiessler.com/newsletter/&quot;&gt;Signup Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;threat-modeling&quot;&gt;Threat Modeling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://segment.com/blog/redefining-threat-modeling/&quot;&gt;Redefining Threat Modeling&lt;/a&gt; - Jeevan Singh from Segment blogs his experience of building a self-serve Threat Modeling program for software engineers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;training&quot;&gt;Training&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Portswigger’s offerings
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://portswigger.net/web-security&quot;&gt;Web Academy + Learning Path + Burp Suite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;TryHackMe
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tryhackme.com&quot;&gt;TryHackMe - Cyber Security Training&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bug-bounties&quot;&gt;Bug Bounties&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1MWWXXRvvesWL8V-GiwGssvg4iDM58_RMeI_SZ65VXwQ/edit#slide=id.p&quot;&gt;JHaddix’s Bug Hunter’s Methodology v4.01&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Familiarize yourself with tools like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/projectdiscovery/nuclei&quot;&gt;project discovery’s nuclei vulnerability scanner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;OWASP’s Amass tool: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OWASP/Amass&quot;&gt;Amass Github Link&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/dnqCt4uUdzc&quot;&gt;Absolute AppSec Amass Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Portswigger Burp Suite: &lt;a href=&quot;https://portswigger.net/burp&quot;&gt;Burp Suite Portswigger Link&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/ZnaRT3HoMn4&quot;&gt;Absolute AppSec Burp Suite Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Radamsa: &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/akihe/radamsa&quot;&gt;radamsa&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/oV0NoYLY0CY&quot;&gt;Absolute AppSec Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;news&quot;&gt;News&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lobste.rs/t/security&quot;&gt;Lobst.rs Security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/netsec&quot;&gt;Reddit Netsec&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/c7HyYGHrkC&quot;&gt;Git-N-formed discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://portswigger.net/daily-swig&quot;&gt;Portswigger Daily Swig&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com&quot;&gt;Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conferences-and-irl&quot;&gt;Conferences and IRL&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.securitybsides.com/w/page/12194138/BSides&quot;&gt;Security BSides&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Low or no cost conferences offered at regional BSides events are a good way to meet infosec people, practice skills in CTF events&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;OWASP - Look for your local OWASP group here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://owasp.org/chapters/&quot;&gt;OWASP Chapters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>@absoluteappsec</name></author><category term="appsec" /><category term="tools" /><category term="resources" /><category term="news" /><category term="appsec" /><category term="tools" /><category term="resources" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Resources that we have found useful during our Application Security Careers</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Three takeaways from an episode with James Kettle</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/appsec/research/http/desync/portswigger/2021/09/21/james-kettle.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Three takeaways from an episode with James Kettle" /><published>2021-09-21T15:46:49-06:00</published><updated>2021-09-21T15:46:49-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/appsec/research/http/desync/portswigger/2021/09/21/james-kettle</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/appsec/research/http/desync/portswigger/2021/09/21/james-kettle.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-portswigger-researchs-james-kettle-approaches-application-security-research&quot;&gt;How Portswigger Research’s James Kettle approaches Application Security Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;80%&quot; preload=&quot;auto&quot; muted=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source src=&quot;/blog/assets/videos/Kettle-promo2.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Absolute AppSec’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b5IVhnboDIY&quot;&gt;147th episode&lt;/a&gt; featured a can’t-miss discussion with James Kettle (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/albinowax&quot;&gt;@albinowax&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter), a world-class exploit researcher from &lt;a href=&quot;https://portswigger.com&quot;&gt;Portswigger&lt;/a&gt;. As the episodes overly dramatic promo highlights, Ken and Seth discovered some interesting details regarding Kettle’s path into security research. But the fun didn’t end there – Kettle provided some valuable insights that could help appsec professionals and bug bounty researchers in furthering their own goals going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;episode-takeaways&quot;&gt;Episode takeaways&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-good-research-serves-as-a-clue-that-there-is-more-good-research-from-that-same-source&quot;&gt;1. Good research serves as a clue that there is more good research from that same source&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the course of the episode, Kettle credited researchers such as (a) orangetsai &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.orange.tw&quot;&gt;(research blog here)&lt;/a&gt;, (b) regilero &lt;a href=&quot;https://regilero.github.io&quot;&gt;(research page here)&lt;/a&gt;
, and (c) Amit Klein &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.securitygalore.com/site3/&quot;&gt;(research here)&lt;/a&gt; as influential touchpoints for Kettle. Kettle’s personal generosity with acknowledgment and respect is also a nice reminder that the security community can be downright collegial: there’s no reason not to be a mensch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-dig-into-something-you-dont-understand&quot;&gt;2. Dig into something you don’t understand&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This works as a way to address many researchers’ desire to play with something new, not just re-creating XSS all day. Kettle’s first introduction to post-smuggling was listening to regilero’s presentation at defcon 24 “Hiding Wookies in HTTP – HTTP smuggling is a thing we should know better and care about,”; &lt;a href=&quot;https://infocondb.org/con/def-con/def-con-24/hiding-wookiees-in-http-http-smuggling-is-a-thing-we-should-know-better-and-care-about&quot;&gt;(infocondb.org)&lt;/a&gt; and Kettle’s first impulse was to tell himself he probably didn’t need to understand HTTP smuggling on any deeper level. However, if you fast forward three years, one can see how much work Kettle did to illuminate HTTP smuggling attacks. For example, read his deep dive and watch his discussion of the technique from defcon 27 – &lt;a href=&quot;https://portswigger.net/research/http-desync-attacks-request-smuggling-reborn&quot;&gt;“HTTP Desync Attacks: Request Smuggling Reborn”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relatedly, Kettle recommends digging into not just exploit vectors, but single applications as well. This is especially true for people looking to increase income in bug bounty research. Truly understanding an application provides greater opportunities for finding the types of vulnerabilities that pay out handsomely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-document-document&quot;&gt;3. Document, Document&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two main points to highlight related to good note-keeping and documentation. First is that a good finding is the key to bug bounty payouts. Show the application owners as articulately and precisely as you can how to re-create your exploit, and your chance of big payouts directly increases. The more long-term benefits for documenting ideas are highlighted by the research trajectory of &lt;em&gt;ALL&lt;/em&gt; Kettle’s ideas. As Kettle relates, he keeps a list of things that might work, will ruminate on how he can create quick tests to check those ideas regardless of whether he considers the idea “smart”; or “dumb”; when it first germinates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, while these were some takeaways we wanted to highlight, the interview provides a lot of insights into the life of a security professional with a well-deserved stellar reputation. Definitely watch &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.com/watch?v=b5IVhnboDIY&quot;&gt;the whole episode&lt;/a&gt;, already one of Absolute AppSec’s most popular, and let us know (by &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@absoluteappsec.com&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; or in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://join.slack.com/t/absoluteappsec/shared_invite/zt-5jay66o6-tOCIelav2VpJjcxRhTBEjA&quot;&gt;slack channel&lt;/a&gt;) if you have any other particular guests you’d like to see on upcoming episodes of the show.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>@absoluteappsec</name></author><category term="appsec" /><category term="research" /><category term="http" /><category term="desync" /><category term="portswigger" /><category term="appsec" /><category term="research" /><category term="http" /><category term="desync" /><category term="portswigger" /><summary type="html">How Portswigger Research’s James Kettle approaches Application Security Research</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dealing with attacks in the Ransomware-as-a-Service era</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/appsec/ransomware/blueteam/defense/2021/07/15/addressing-ransomware.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dealing with attacks in the Ransomware-as-a-Service era" /><published>2021-07-15T15:46:49-06:00</published><updated>2021-07-15T15:46:49-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/appsec/ransomware/blueteam/defense/2021/07/15/addressing-ransomware</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/appsec/ransomware/blueteam/defense/2021/07/15/addressing-ransomware.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;addressing-ransomware-in-organizations-and-application-security&quot;&gt;Addressing Ransomware in Organizations and Application Security&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Pv7twtQxB6Y&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[For an attacker], where there’s an absence from technical protection, there’s always the presence of human error.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;KEN JOHNSON (@cktricky)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ransomware is everywhere! The international news regarding the May 2021 ransomware attack on Colonial Pipeline and the subsequent service shutoff affecting consumers throughout the U.S. southeast put launched ransomware into headlines and general awareness. Seth and Ken reflect on the topic in this episode, and, with contributions from some Absolute AppSec Clack community members, discuss the increasing frequency of ransomware-style attacks. Even when the exploits don’t receive headlines with the notoriety of colonial pipeline, it’s evident that ransomware is a problem that isn’t going away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a wide-ranging discussion on the topic, Seth and Ken providing historical overviews of security responses to the ransomware class of attacks as well as some basic security hygiene tips which can help an organization counteract the worst effects of ransomware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The need to introduce redundancy in your system operations and to design the security of your infrastructure with pre-mortem attack exercises were the two main points raised during discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Redundancy is one of the main avenues organizations use for preventing ransomware attacks. If [an attacker] does get in (just assume that inevitably someone is going to click on a link), the attacker is going to encrypt the data on a file share. You need to (1) identify that attack, and (2) restore the system to a known good point before the encryption happened.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;SETH LAW (@sethlaw)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Ken, ransomware, when addressed a decade ago, faced a security point-of-view that aimed to prevent attacks with a tough exterior defense. Once that exterior defense were breached, there were no planned-for interior defenses, and attackers could feast on the gooey insides of security infrastructures. Pre-mortem planning reflects an evolution in security planning for ransomware. Security planners now assume attackers can find a way in, so organizations need to strategize their responses when the inevitable happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To catch up on more of Ken and Seth’s discussion, check out the rest of this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pKNdvUcpiYY&quot;&gt;episode here on youtube&lt;/a&gt;, or search for Absolute AppSec on your preferred podcast service.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>@absoluteappsec</name></author><category term="appsec" /><category term="ransomware" /><category term="blueteam" /><category term="defense" /><category term="appsec" /><category term="ransomware" /><category term="blueteam" /><category term="defense" /><summary type="html">Addressing Ransomware in Organizations and Application Security</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Client-Side Solve: Browser Sanitization APIs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/browser/client/appsec/apis/2021/07/01/browser-sanitization-apis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Client-Side Solve: Browser Sanitization APIs" /><published>2021-07-01T15:46:49-06:00</published><updated>2021-07-01T15:46:49-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/browser/client/appsec/apis/2021/07/01/browser-sanitization-apis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/browser/client/appsec/apis/2021/07/01/browser-sanitization-apis.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-browser-sanitization-apis-could-usher-in-a-new-era-of-client-side-security&quot;&gt;Why Browser Sanitization APIs could usher in a new era of client-side security?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/bUtaE6D2jf0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April 2021, Google and Firefox both announced that a &lt;a href=&quot;https://portswigger.net/daily-swig/google-and-mozilla-unveil-plans-to-bake-html-sanitization-into-their-browsers&quot;&gt;sanitization API&lt;/a&gt; would be integrated within their browsers. Ken Johnson (cktricky) and Seth Law (sethlaw) discussed these new developments on the Absolute AppSec podcast with a good deal more sanguinity than regular podcast listeners may be accustomed to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the two hosts, the browser update could go along way toward addressing client-side vulnerabilities, especially certain cross-site scripting weaknesses. Sanitized languages can drastically reduce attack surfaces, helping prevent potential attacks. And Mozilla and Google’s partnership with Cure53 represents a natural alliance in developing a browser-side response to many Cross-Site Scripting attacks. Developers have already used Cure53’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cure53/DOMPurify&quot;&gt;DOMPurify&lt;/a&gt; libraries to positive affect in reducing attack surfaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/images/xss.svg&quot; alt=&quot;XSS&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Seth Law’s view, the sanitization API is analogous to earlier library-adoption methods to reduce the threat of SQL Injection attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;SQL Injection was a problem for years until the underlying way we passed data to databases changed….The number of exploits we saw dropped drastically because of the way we changed the underlying technology and the way developers interacted with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Browser Sanitization makes sense as a technology solution that could standardize how developers address html content that accepts client-side data. Seeing how the Browser Sanitization API works going forward could reduce the onus on developers in solving the problem of XSS attacks by researching and implementing the correct bespoke library for their own organization’s purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see more of Ken and Seth’s discussion of Browser Sanitization API’s, among other topics, checkout the youtube broadcast &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zsN2FNoUZIc&amp;amp;amp&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Subscribe to our youtube &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCo9CDrIB0rJwG4GGz8CZEaQ&quot;&gt;channel&lt;/a&gt; to be made aware of new content. Absolute AppSec covers Application Security content in weekly YouTube livestreams buttressed with lively discussion in our &lt;a href=&quot;absoluteappsec.slack.com&quot;&gt;Slack Channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To read a more academic discussion of Cure53’s work, see Mario Heiderich, Christopher Späth, and Jörg Schwenk’s research paper &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-319-66399-9_7&quot;&gt;“DOMPurify: Client-Side Protection Against XSS and Markup Injection,” in &lt;em&gt;European Symposium on Research in Computer Security&lt;/em&gt; 2017: 116-134&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Researchers can also look at Cure53’s all-encompassing &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cure53/browser-sec-whitepaper/blob/master/browser-security-whitepaper.pdf&quot;&gt;Browser Security White Paper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;back&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>@absoluteappsec</name></author><category term="browser" /><category term="client" /><category term="appsec" /><category term="apis" /><category term="browser" /><category term="client" /><category term="appsec" /><category term="apis" /><summary type="html">Why Browser Sanitization APIs could usher in a new era of client-side security?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Two tensions governing privacy and data</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/data/privacy/appsec/consumer/2021/05/04/data-privacy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Two tensions governing privacy and data" /><published>2021-05-04T15:46:49-06:00</published><updated>2021-05-04T15:46:49-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/data/privacy/appsec/consumer/2021/05/04/data-privacy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/data/privacy/appsec/consumer/2021/05/04/data-privacy.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;discussing-data-and-privacy-with-abinecom-cofounder-rob-shavell&quot;&gt;Discussing data and privacy with Abine.com cofounder Rob Shavell&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/images/data-privacy.png&quot; alt=&quot;Protecting Data and Privacy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an interesting episode of Absolute Appsec &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PgyyCDiIzY4&quot;&gt;133&lt;/a&gt;, Seth and Ken interviewed Abine.com cofounder Rob Shavell in a wide-ranging discussion concerning data and privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the historical context, according to Shavell, consumers have largely been persuaded that the promise of technology was worth ceding some privacy. But, since 2016 especially, social media users and online consumers have been made aware of the pitfalls of data tracking and the ways it can be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/operational-security/big-data/how-to-access-the-voter-information-dirt-cambridge-analytica-has-on-you/a/d-id/741564?_mc=rss_x_drr_edt_aud_dr_x_x-rss-simple&quot;&gt;exploited&lt;/a&gt;. If there is a tension between privacy and the promise of data-sharing, Shavell sees that a modicum of balance between these two values could start to be restored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;General Data Protection Regulation (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portswigger.net/daily-swig/gdpr&quot;&gt;GDPR&lt;/a&gt;) rules addressing privacy rights in Europe, are increasingly informing emerging privacy/data legal frameworks and future expectations concerning them in the United States. Shavell sees this as a positive development and a new phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming from a background in venture spaces, Shavell has seen how his once contrarian stance
that prioritized privacy over the technological offerings of data collection and sharing has been significantly mainstreamed. As a result, there’s money behind the interest in data and privacy protection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For entrepreneurial developers, that means opportunity. Consumers who choosing from among several products or startup are much more likely to opt for or switch to the alternative that best protects personal data and privacy. And the rapid consumer adoption of Abine’s privacy suite: &lt;a href=&quot;https://joindeleteme.com&quot;&gt;DeleteMe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.abine.com&quot;&gt;Blur&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dnt.abine.com/#feature/tracking&quot;&gt;tracker blocker&lt;/a&gt; highlights increased interest in protecting personal data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second tension discussed in the episode related to the responsibility of developers in keeping privacy protections in mind while they work. &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/PgyyCDiIzY4?t=2523&quot;&gt;Seth’s question&lt;/a&gt; elicited a considered response from Shavell. “Privacy by design” is a nice idea, according to Shavell, but decisions concerning how data is used is typically outside the developer’s authority. However, after Ken raised the concern of legal ramifications of a company’s exposure after potential data breaches, everybody agreed that there are significant incentives for developers to pay early attention to data protection in design phases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, there are reasons for optimism even with the privacy threats illustrated by technology that can be exploited (See, governments’ potential usage of facial recognition or AI). Please watch the rest of the episode &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PgyyCDiIzY4&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, subscribe to &lt;a href=&quot;https://absoluteappsec.com&quot;&gt;Absolute Appsec&lt;/a&gt;, or listen to us on your preferred podcasting platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/PgyyCDiIzY4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>@absoluteappsec</name></author><category term="data" /><category term="privacy" /><category term="appsec" /><category term="consumer" /><category term="data" /><category term="privacy" /><category term="appsec" /><category term="consumer" /><summary type="html">Discussing data and privacy with Abine.com cofounder Rob Shavell</summary></entry></feed>